const data = {
  "Music": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of music notation?",
      "options": ["Standard notation", "Tab notation", "Morse code notation", "Graphics notation"],
      "answer": "Morse code notation",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "What is the most common time signature in classical music?",
      "options": ["3/4", "4/4", "5/4", "6/8"],
      "answer": "4/4",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of instrument in a symphony orchestra?",
      "options": ["Violin", "Piano", "Harp", "Theremin"],
      "answer": "Theremin",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "What is the most common key in pop music?",
      "options": ["C Major", "G Major", "D Major", "A Major"],
      "answer": "C Major",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of chord?",
      "options": ["Major", "Minor", "Diminished", "Flat"],
      "answer": "Flat",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of music genre?",
      "options": ["Jazz", "Blues", "Rock", "Applesauce"],
      "answer": "Applesauce",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of music theory?",
      "options": ["Harmony", "Counterpoint", "Form", "Cooking"],
      "answer": "Cooking",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "What is the most common tempo marking in classical music?",
      "options": ["Allegro", "Andante", "Adagio", "Moderato"],
      "answer": "Allegro",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of musical form?",
      "options": ["Sonata", "Symphony", "Concerto", "Spaghetti"],
      "answer": "Spaghetti",
      "category": "music"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of music notation software?",
      "options": ["Sibelius", "Finale", "MuseScore", "Microsoft Word"],
      "answer": "Microsoft Word",
      "category": "music"
    }
  ],
  "Modern-Art": [
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "Which artist is known for coining the term 'Surrealism'?",
      "options": ["Pablo Picasso", "Salvador Dali", "Vincent van Gogh", "Henri Matisse"],
      "answer": "Salvador Dali",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Which movement is associated with the use of abstract forms and shapes in art?",
      "options": ["Impressionism", "Expressionism", "Futurism", "Cubism"],
      "answer": "Cubism",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Which artist is known for painting the work 'The Persistence of Memory'?",
      "options": ["Pablo Picasso", "Salvador Dali", "Vincent van Gogh", "Henri Matisse"],
      "answer": "Salvador Dali",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "Which artist is known for creating the painting 'The Scream'?",
      "options": ["Vincent van Gogh", "Salvador Dali", "Edvard Munch", "Claude Monet"],
      "answer": "Edvard Munch",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What movement was associated with the use of bold, bright colors and thick brushstrokes?",
      "options": ["Impressionism", "Expressionism", "Fauvism", "Cubism"],
      "answer": "Fauvism",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "What movement was associated with the use of bright colors, simplified forms, and a focus on movement and speed",
      "options": ["Impressionism", "Futurism", "Surrealism", "Abstract Expressionism"],
      "answer": "Futurism",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "Which artist is known for creating the painting 'Water Lilies'?",
      "options": ["Claude Monet", "Paul Cezanne", "Paul Gauguin", "Paul Klee"],
      "answer": "Claude Monet",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Which artist is known for creating the painting 'Les Demoiselles d'Avignon'?",
      "options": ["Henri Matisse", "Vincent van Gogh", "Salvador Dali", "Pablo Picasso"],
      "answer": "Pablo Picasso",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "Which artist is known for creating the painting 'Guernica'?",
      "options": ["Claude Mone", "Paul Cezanne", "Pablo Picasso", "Vincent van Gogh"],
      "answer": "Pablo Picasso",
      "category": "modern-art"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which artist is known for creating the sculpture 'The Thinker'?",
      "options": ["Auguste Rodin", "Alexander Calder", "Jean Arp", "Henry Moore"],
      "answer": "Auguste Rodin",
      "category": "modern-art"
    }
  ],
  "Coding": [
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "What is the correct syntax for an if statement in Python?",
      "options": ["if (condition):", "if condition", "if: condition", "if condition:"],
      "answer": "if condition:",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a data type in JavaScript?",
      "options": ["String", "Number", "Boolean", "ArrayList"],
      "answer": "ArrayList",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "Which of the following is used to declare a variable in Java?",
      "options": ["var", "let", "const", "int"],
      "answer": "int",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "What is the correct syntax for a for loop in C#?",
      "options": ["for i = 0 to 10", "for (i = 0; i <= 10; i++)", "for (int i = 0; i <= 10)", "for i in range(0, 10)"],
      "answer": "for (i = 0; i <= 10; i++)",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a looping structure in PHP?",
      "options": ["while", "for", "do-while", "foreach"],
      "answer": "foreach",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a valid operator in C++?",
      "options": ["+", "-", "*", "$"],
      "answer": "$",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "In which programming language is 'print' used for displaying output?",
      "options": ["Python", "JavaScript", "Java", "C++"],
      "answer": "Python",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "What is the correct syntax for a function in Ruby?",
      "options": ["function name()", "def name", "function name", "def name()"],
      "answer": "def name()",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a type of variable in Swift?",
      "options": ["Int", "String", "Double", "Object"],
      "answer": "Object",
      "category": "coding"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "In which programming language is '#' used for commenting?",
      "options": ["Python", "JavaScript", "Java", "C++"],
      "answer": "C++",
      "category": "coding"
    }
  ]
};

// Global variables
let currentCategory = "";
let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
let selectedAnswers = {};

// DOM elements
const categoryButtonsContainer = document.getElementById("category-buttons");
const quizContainer = document.getElementById("quiz-container");
const categoryTitle = document.getElementById("category-title");
const questionText = document.getElementById("question-text");
const optionsContainer = document.getElementById("options-container");
const prevButton = document.getElementById("prev-button");
const nextButton = document.getElementById("next-button");
const submitButton = document.getElementById("submit-button");
const boxHeaderDiv = document.getElementById("box");

// Render category buttons
for (const category in data) {
  const categoryButton = document.createElement("button");
  categoryButton.classList.add("category-button");
  categoryButton.innerText = category;
  categoryButton.addEventListener("click", () => loadCategory(category));
  if(localStorage.getItem(category) != null){
    categoryButton.style.backgroundColor = 'grey';
    categoryButton.disabled = true;
  }
  categoryButtonsContainer.appendChild(categoryButton);
}

// Load questions from selected category
function loadCategory(category) {
  currentCategory = category;
  currentQuestionIndex = 0;
  selectedAnswers = {};

  renderQuestion();
  updateNavigationButtons();
  categoryButtonsContainer.style.display = "none";
  quizContainer.style.display = "block";
}

// Render current question
function renderQuestion() {
  
  boxHeaderDiv.style.display = "none";
  nextButton.disabled = true;
  const questions = data[currentCategory];
  const currentQuestion = questions[currentQuestionIndex];
  categoryTitle.innerText = currentCategory;
  questionText.innerText = (currentQuestionIndex + 1) + '. ' + currentQuestion.question;

  optionsContainer.innerHTML = "";
  
  currentQuestion.options.forEach((option) => {
    const optionContainer = document.createElement("div");
    optionContainer.classList.add("option-container");

    const radioInput = document.createElement("input");
    radioInput.type = "radio";
    radioInput.name = "answer";
    radioInput.value = option;
    
    if(currentCategory != undefined && option != undefined 
      && localStorage.getItem(currentCategory + '_' + currentQuestion.id) != null
      && localStorage.getItem(currentCategory + '_' + currentQuestion.id) == option){
        radioInput.checked = 'checked';
    }
    radioInput.id = option; 
    radioInput.addEventListener("change", () => {
      selectedAnswers[currentQuestion.id] = option;
      updateNavigationButtons();
    });
    const optionLabel = document.createElement("label");
    optionLabel.innerText = option;
    optionContainer.appendChild(radioInput);
    optionContainer.appendChild(optionLabel);
    optionsContainer.appendChild(optionContainer);
  });
  updateNavigationButtons();
}
function updateNavigationButtons() {
  const questions = data[currentCategory];
  const currentQuestion = questions[currentQuestionIndex];
  prevButton.disabled = currentQuestionIndex === 0;
  nextButton.disabled = !selectedAnswers[currentQuestion.id];
  if(selectedAnswers[currentQuestion.id] != undefined 
    && selectedAnswers[currentQuestion.id] != null) {
    localStorage.setItem(currentCategory + '_' + currentQuestion.id, selectedAnswers[currentQuestion.id]);
      
  }
  if (currentQuestionIndex === questions.length - 1) {
    nextButton.style.visibility = "hidden";
    submitButton.style.display = "inline-block";
  } else {
    nextButton.style.visibility = "visible";
    submitButton.style.display = "none";
  }
  if(localStorage.getItem(currentCategory+'_'+currentQuestion.id) != null){
    nextButton.disabled = false;
  }
}
// Function to handle the next button click
function handleNext() {
  if (currentQuestionIndex < data[currentCategory].length - 1) {
    currentQuestionIndex++;
    renderQuestion();
  }
}

// Function to handle the previous button click
function handlePrevious() {
  if (currentQuestionIndex > 0) {
    currentQuestionIndex--;
    renderQuestion();
  }
  
}


// Function to handle the submit button click
function handleSubmit() {
  // Calculate the marks or score
  let score = 0;
  const questions = data[currentCategory];
  for (let i = 0; i < questions.length; i++) {
    const question = questions[i];
    console.log('selected : ' , selectedAnswers[question.id]);
    console.log('correct : ' , question.answer);
    if (selectedAnswers[question.id] === question.answer) {
      score++;
    }
  }
  
  // Display the score
  
  const scoreContainer = document.getElementById("popup-text");
  scoreContainer.textContent = `Your Score: ${score}/${questions.length}`;
  scoreContainer.style.display = "block";
  
  // Disable the next and previous buttons
  nextButton.disabled = true;
  prevButton.disabled = true;
  // submitButton.style.display = "none";
  console.log(currentCategory);
  console.log(selectedAnswers);
  localStorage.setItem(currentCategory, true);
  openPopup();
}


function openPopup() {
  var popupContainer = document.getElementById("popupContainer");
  document.body.classList.add("popup-active");
  popupContainer.style.display = "block";
}

// Close the pop-up
function closePopup() {
  var popupContainer = document.getElementById("popupContainer");
  document.body.classList.remove("popup-active");
  popupContainer.style.display = "none";
}

// Add event listeners to the buttons
nextButton.addEventListener("click", handleNext);
prevButton.addEventListener("click", handlePrevious);
submitButton.addEventListener("click", handleSubmit);


